Yousef Elkammar

Student at Faculty of Computers and Information Sciences, Ain Shams University.

An undergraduate in computer science with humbled experience using C++, Python, Java, Flutter, SQL, and Source Control. I want to put my skills to develop an outstanding applications for common use.

Work History

Android Committee member. 2020-11 to Present.

MSP-Tech Club -ASU, Cairo.

- Learning basic and trending technologies in Android App development as recycler view, MVVM, REST API, Retrofit and Room DB.
- Completing weekly tasks and projects.
- Preparing for being summer training technical support.
- Making comprehensive project that includes all what we learned.
- Improving soft skills as we practice and lecture every session.

Volunteer.

2022-02 to 2022-04.

ASU Career Center, Cairo.

- Adhered to organization procedures and instructions to maintain safety for program participants and other workers.
- Met with other volunteers and program leaders to discuss new service opportunities.
- Responsible for evaluating sign up requests.
- Registration team member.

Mobile Development Intern.

2022-02 - 2022-03

The Sparks Foundation, Remote

- Developed a login app that integrates Facebook and Google login APIs.
- Helped fellow interns on their tasks and inquiries.
- Gave Peer Evaluation for fellow interns' projects based on design, code architecture and responsiveness.
- Expanded my social network as it was a mandatory task of the intern.

Trainee

2022-02 - 2022-03

ITI Menoufiya's Branch., Remote.

- Developed a to do list application with responsive design.
- Acquired certificates of completion of Mobile Application Development using Java, SQLITE and Freelancing.

Education

Sophomore B.Sc. Computer Science.

2020-10 to Present

Faculty of Computers and Information Sciences - Ain Shams University.

- GPA: 3.2.
- Awarded Certificate of honor for Flutter 22'workshop -best project (1st).
- Awarded Certificate of honor for Structured Programming -best project (top 5).
- Professional development completed in Web, Android and Flutter app development.
- Studying basic science fields of math, probability and programming.

Contact

Address

Qalyup, Qalyupiya, 11816

Phone & WhatsApp

+20 155 093 5404

E-mail

20201701158@cis.asu.edu.eg Yousefabdelhamed113@gmail.com

LinkedIn

Yousef Elkammar

Github

RedBiscuits

Skills

Java.

Used daily in **android development**. Implemented in: **Blackjack**, **To-do**—**list** and **Login app**.

Python.

Used daily in **AI** and **machine learning**. Implemented in **Muzify** music app, **Heart Failure Prediction**, **Statistical Analysis** and **AI** Curriculums.

C++.

Used in **problem solving**. Implemented in **Flappy Bird game's engine and graphics**, **Data Structures** and problem solving

OOP.

Used in **Android** and **DS**.

Implemented in **To-do List app**, **Login app**and **android**.

Android Development.

Used in **Applications Development**. Implemented in: **To-do List app, Login app, WhatsApp clone** and daily practice.

Source Control.

Used in **learning** and **college** projects

Problem Solving.

Used in **developing constructive thinking**.

Implemented in: Codeforces problems.

REST APIs.

Used in **Android Development**. Implemented in: **Login app**.

SQLITE.

Used in **Applications Development** (Flutter and Android).
Implemented in: Muzify and To-do List app.

Flutter.

Used in **Applications Development**. Implemented in: **Muzify**.

Basic Web Development. Used in First year summer training.

Implemented in: Pharaohs website.

Certifications

2022-02

Certificate of honor for Flutter best project (1st).

2021-08

Certificate of honor for Structured Programming best project (top 5).

2022-03

Certificate of attendance for Git/Github source control workshop.

2022-02

Certificate of attendance for Flutter workshop.

2022-02

Certificate of completion for JavaSE development course.

2022-03

Certificate of completion for Android App development course.

2022-02

Certificate of completion for Database Fundamentals course.

Projects

Chat App:

2022-3 to present (in development).

Java, Firebase, Design pattern (SOLID) and Android.

Chat application that mimics WhatsApp with its most important features (video calls, stories, one-to-one chat login and phone verification)

Was made for college Data Structure curriculum.

Muzify (Music player and downloader) app:

2022-2 to 2022-3.

Dart, Flutter, SQFLite, Python3 and Flask.

Music player and downloader that has its own backend on local device as it queries YouTube through its URL and downloads the required song as mp3 without any Ads and 1 time download then it's possible to play the songs through built-in music player.

To-do List app:

2022-2-12 to 2022-2-28.

Android, Java, SQLite3.

Task managing app which facilitates taking notes and setting tasks.

Flappy Bird game:

2021-3 to 2021-5.

C++, SFML.

Flappy Bird remake with C++ and SFML library from scratch, game engine and graphics were also remade.

Pharos website: 2021-7 to 2021-8.

HTML, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and Apache.

Website that shows Egypt's tourist attractions and scenic spots with the availability to book tickets in Egypt.

Heart Disease Prediction models:

2021-11 to 2021-12.

Python3, Sickit-learn and seaborn libraries.

Program that predicts heart failure based on medical tests with accuracies of 91%, 78% and 55% for Decision tree, KNN and multiple linear regression respectively.

Blackjack game: 2022-12-04 to 2022-12-19.

Java, Swing.

Blackjack poker game without bets or coins and with powerful GUI.

Software Development Lifecycle.

General knowledge of **how software products are made**

Relational Databases.

Used in **Application Development**. Implemented in: **Restaurant Management System**, **To-do List app** and **Pharaohs website**.

Research.

Able to **search** and **extract** information without previous knowledge.

Public speaking.

Used to discuss projects, lecture, and handle customers in earlier jobs.

Team collaboration.

Used to be **team leader** in college projects when I'm the best fit for and **collaborate** with colleagues and fellows in MSP.

English.

Professional level
(Spoken and written).
Used daily in studying fields,
Communication and technical
writing